# **OGUNKANMI AYODELE**

(+234) 70-64990334 | ayo4oyo@gmail.com

Linkedin: ayodele-ogunkanmi/ | Github: drpompin | https://ayodeleogunkanmi.vercel.app

# Summary

Frontend developer with 3 years experience in frontend web development using HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript/JQuery, React, Apollo Client and Redux to deliver high end user responsive web interfaces.

Looking to implement my skills to provide web solutions to clients, businesses and organizations and to find an enabling environment that supports growth and rewards hard work.

# **Skills & Highlights**

- Proficient knowledge of JavaScript, JQuery, ReactJS, GraphQL(Apollo Client), Redux, React Hooks, TypeScript, Googling
- Proficient knowledge of HTML, CSS, SASS
- Invaluable experience working on projects that utilize Git, Apollo Client, Fetch API, AJAX, JSON, NextJS, Bootstrap, Styled-components, Material-UI and ES6
- Knowledge and use of Node, Python, SQL, Webpack
- Knowledge of testing with Jest and Enzyme
- Responsive Web Development, Agile development model, Cross-browser compatibility, Version control

#### **Professional Experience**

## Freelancing and Personal Development Projects (March 2020 - Present)

- Worked as a frontend developer on a mobile responsive e-commerce website; utilising ReactJS/NextJS, ApolloClient/GraphQl, Styled-Components, Material-UI e.t.c.
- Built a custom website for a restaurant with ReactJS, managed the state with Redux and implemented the styling using styled-components
- Developed an e-commerce website that uses ReactJS/NextJS, GraphQL Yoga, Prisma, Apollo-client for data management: performing GraphQL mutations, fetching GraphQL queries, caching GraphQL data, managing local state, Error and local UI states and testing with Jest and Enzyme.

#### Sendbox Software Technologies, Lagos - Junior Frontend Developer (August 2017 - February 2019)

- Developed reusable React components and designed responsive web pages/components based on specified designs for different company projects.
- Implemented addition of extra functionalities on the request of clients' to ease their stress of doing business.
- Implemented upload and download workflow that ensured efficient availability of clients' publications for download and online viewing.
- Designed and automated a dashboard with complete functionalities that enabled administrative staff to act on shipment complaints; this significantly reduced the time taken to close customer issues by over 100%.
- Actively participated in the development and implementation of booking and payment workflows that enabled clients to book shipments from their mobile devices, increasing shipment bookings by 200%+ and signups by over 50% for consecutive weeks.
- Utilized whimsical online tool to create mockup and wireframe designs.
- Employed github/bitbucket for collaboration and version control; collaborated with other team members on the development of different company projects.

#### Education

Osun State University, Osogbo, Osun State (August 2009 - April 2015)
B.Sc. Biochemistry, 2nd class upper division.

### Certifications

• Google Africa Challenge Scholarship: Front-End

Languages: English.